<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<MetadataType xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="https://www.fgdc.gov/schemas/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.xsd">
    <idinfo>
        <citation>
            <citeinfo>
                <origin>Alaska Department of Natural Resources - Information Resource Management</origin>
                <pubdate>20190822</pubdate>
                <title>Alaska Boroughs</title>
                <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
                <onlink>http://asgdc.alaska.gov#40</onlink>
            </citeinfo>
        </citation>
        <descript>
            <abstract>This data contains the borough boundaries.

The borough boundaries came from various sources. The Kenai Peninsula Borough and
the Municipality of Anchorage boundaries were received in digital form from those
agencies. The Land &amp; Peninsula Borough and the City &amp; Borough of Yakutat were entered
from legal descriptions. The City &amp; Borough of Yakutat boundary was changed in 1997.
Update edits were provided by the Alaska Department of Community and Regional Affairs.
The Denali Borough was digitized from an official map from the Department of Regional
and Community Affairs. All other boroughs were extracted from the 1990 TIGER database
and snapped to the township grid coverage. All boundaries have been checked against
their legal descriptions.</abstract>
            <purpose>This data was created for mapping.</purpose>
            <supplinf>Procedures_Used: Combined the coverages BORO and REAA. This coverage was created on
February 29 1996 by UNIONing the BORO and REAA coverages with a 1 meter fuzzy tolerance
using the following ARC command:

UNION BORO REAA &lt;WORK_COVER&gt; 1 JOIN

In ARCEDIT overlap polygons were identified by selecting for instances where the item
BORONAME was blank. 31 polygons were identified and arcs were then selected  and deleted
based on the BORO coverage. An item called NAME was added to the .PAT and this item was
populated from the BORONAME items. The item SID was populated for the boroughs from the
NUM item. All extraneous items were dropped. LABELERRORS were resolved by selecting for
cover-id ne $ID and deleting the selected labels. PSEUDO NODES were resolved with: UNSPLIT
NONE.

Annotation subclasses were renamed to show if they pertain to Boroughs -- BORO prefix. A
Redefined item -- TYPE -- was added to provide an easy method for selecting all
Boroughs - SEL TYPE = B.

It was determined that the southerly boundary of the Northwest Arctic Borough was approximately
27 meters north of its proper location. This boundary was replaced by selecting the appropriate
arcs from the TWPSPOLY coverage and putting them into the BOROREAA coverage. The incorrect arcs
were then deleted.

The REGION.TYPE feature was created based on TYPE by adding an ITEM called REG_TYPE and CALCing
REG_TYPE = TYPE. The ITEM REG_TYPE was dropped once the feature was created. REGIONS may be selected
using the same selection criteria as for polygons.

Revisions:

19960611: Adjusted Northerly boundary of CBJ.

19960530 D. Mortenson Corrected Artic to Arctic in border1mil annotation. Also built each of the
annotation subclasses.

19960611: In ARCEDIT- Ron Van Pelt moved the northerly boundary of the CBJ to 58 58.3N 135 13.2W
and 58 57 44.96N 133 10 13.94 W. The first point was select from the NGSMON coverage - Station ELD
- in ALBERS and the boundary snapped to it. The location of the second point was identified in the
TWPSPOLY coverage and the boundary snapped to it. All work was accomplished in ARCEDIT.

City &amp; Borough of Yakutat entered from legal description by J. Tam 19921012.

Annotation for borough names added by J. Tam 199212. Uses textset font61.txt.

Additional annotation added 199401 based on scale of map. Modifications 19940303 by J. Tam: Annotation
edits to subclasses anno2mil and anno1mil. Changed leader arrows to extend into borough polygons.

Added Juneau borough annexation 199403 by J. Tam (effective 19940101): Boundary drawn by R. van
Pelt on 1:250000 USGS quad from legal description then digitized and snapped to known lat/long
points. QC by R. van Pelt.

Modifications 19940310 by J. Tam: Annotation edit to subclass anno2mil Reposition annotation for
North Slope Borough.

Modifications 199405 by J. Tam: Reposition annotation for Fairbanks North Star Borough.

Modifications 19940804 by J. Tam: Added annotation subclass anno1mil_sw for SW regional map only.

Modifications 19940829 by J. Tam: Added item SID to boro.pat. Modifications 19950113 by
J. Tam: Edits to the North Slope Borough boundaries: Replaced offshore boundary with arcs
from the 3-mile limit coverage net/beluga/ads_db/data1/statewide/ak_bndy. Replace southern
and eastern boundaries with arcs from coverage created by R. VanPelt who used /net/beluga/db/sections/new_k
and new_u; net/beluga/db/alaska/grids/ll1x1 and itma.

19950421 K Zeiner Replaced the Canadian border in southeast with the border from the net/beluga/db/alaska/grids/twpspoly.

19959720 - J. Tam Unsplit arcs. Placed nodes at qmq borders to facilitate use of POLYGONBORDERTEXT
command when making qmq plots.

NOTE: The Kenai Peninsula Borough and Municipality of Anchorage boundaries were received in digital
format. The Denali Borough was digitized from an official map. All other boroughs were taken from
the Tiger database and snapped to the TWPSPOLY coverage.

the names of the REAAs.

Week of 19940207 QC by Dave Luck and Scott Pexton.

Edits 19940304 by J. Tam Corrections were made according to the list compiled by Dave Luck and Scott Pexton:

Boroughs were removed so that the coverage contained only REAAs. The 20 REAAs were renumbered to follow the
list on the Dept. of Community and Regional Affairs (DCRA) Community/Borough Map dated 1993.

19940826 - J. Tam and S. Pexton A polygon around Skagway was added to the Chatham REAA. St. Matthew Island
was designated Undetermined because it does not come under any REAA. SID values were recoded to 3-letter
codes for loading to LAS.

Modifications 19950113 by J. Tam: Replace northern boundaries of Yukon-Koyukuk and Yukon Flats REAAs
shared with North Slope Borough) with arcs from coverage created by R. VanPelt who used /net/beluga/db/sections/new_k and new_u;
net/beluga/db/alaska/grids/ll1x1 and itma.

19950421 K Zeiner Replaced the Canadian border in southeast with the border from the /net/beluga/db/alaska/grids/twpspoly.

199712 D. Mortenson Modified Yakutat and Adak, as described in Abstract.

Reviews_Applied_to_Data: Boundaries were cross referenced with legal description by Ron VanPelt 199602292.
The 199712 modifications were not cross referenced.

199912 M. Gorham Added b2mil_rdb annotation subclass. This is a slight modification of the boro2mil -
so there is not conflict with the recording district boundaries.

20050930 M. Martin Adjusted boundary between Denali and Matanuska-Susitna Boroughs as follows;
Northeast corner of section 25, 18S, 3W Fairbanks Meridian, following the section line west to the
intersection of Denali National Park.

20130204 T. Moody Added Petersburg Borough. Petersburg Borough incorporates approximately 3,365 square miles of land and 982 square miles of water. Approved August 22, 2012.

Standard Map Depiction:
An ArcGIS layer file, downloadable at http://dnr.alaska.gov/lrisservices/ls_proxy/document?static_pickup=borough_boundary.zip, is available for use in creating a standard map rendition.</supplinf>
        </descript>
        <timeperd>
            <timeinfo>
                <sngdate>
                    <caldate>20190822</caldate>
                </sngdate>
            </timeinfo>
            <current>Date of data extraction</current>
        </timeperd>
        <status>
            <update>As needed.</update>
        </status>
        <spdom/>
        <keywords>
            <theme>
                <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
                <themekey>boundaries</themekey>
            </theme>
            <theme>
                <themekt>none</themekt>
                <themekey>Borough boundaries</themekey>
                <themekey>counties</themekey>
                <themekey>cadastral</themekey>
            </theme>
            <place>
                <placekt>none</placekt>
                <placekey>Alaska</placekey>
                <placekey>Alaska Gateway</placekey>
                <placekey>Aleutian</placekey>
                <placekey>Aleutian East</placekey>
                <placekey>Anchorage</placekey>
                <placekey>Annette Island</placekey>
                <placekey>Bristol Bay</placekey>
                <placekey>Chatham</placekey>
                <placekey>Chugach</placekey>
                <placekey>Copper River</placekey>
                <placekey>Delta/Greely</placekey>
                <placekey>Denali</placekey>
                <placekey>Fairbanks</placekey>
                <placekey>Haines</placekey>
                <placekey>Iditarod</placekey>
                <placekey>Juneau</placekey>
                <placekey>Kashunamiut</placekey>
                <placekey>Kenai</placekey>
                <placekey>Kodiak Island</placekey>
                <placekey>Kuspuk</placekey>
                <placekey>Lake &amp; Peninsula</placekey>
                <placekey>Lower Kuskokwim</placekey>
                <placekey>Lower Yukon</placekey>
                <placekey>Mat-Su</placekey>
                <placekey>Matanuska-Susitna</placekey>
                <placekey>North Slope</placekey>
                <placekey>North Star</placekey>
                <placekey>Northwest Arctic</placekey>
                <placekey>Pribilof Island</placekey>
                <placekey>Sitka</placekey>
                <placekey>Skagway</placekey>
                <placekey>Southwest</placekey>
                <placekey>Yakutat</placekey>
                <placekey>Yukon Flats</placekey>
                <placekey>Yukon-Koyukuk</placekey>
                <placekey>Yupiit</placekey>
            </place>
        </keywords>
        <accconst>To ensure distribution of the most current public information, please refer
requests for data or products to the Alaska Department of Natural Resources,
Information Resource Management.</accconst>
        <useconst>It is not recommended the data be used at a scale larger than 1:250,000.

Any hardcopies or published datasets utilizing these data sets shall clearly
indicate their source. If the user has modified the data in any way they are
obligated to describe the types of modifications they have performed. User
specifically agrees not to misrepresent these data sets, nor to imply that
changes they made were approved by the Alaska Department of Natural Resources.</useconst>
        <ptcontac>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntperp>
                    <cntper>GIS Public Access Coordinator</cntper>
                    <cntorg>AK Department of Natural Resources - Information Resource Management</cntorg>
                </cntperp>
                <cntpos>GIS Public Access Coordinator</cntpos>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
                    <address>550 W. 7th Suite 706</address>
                    <city>Anchorage</city>
                    <state>AK</state>
                    <postal>99501</postal>
                    <country>USA</country>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>907 269 8060</cntvoice>
                <cntfax>907 269 8920</cntfax>
                <cntemail>dnr.gispub@alaska.gov</cntemail>
                <hours>800-1600 AST</hours>
                <cntinst>See Distribution_Information</cntinst>
            </cntinfo>
        </ptcontac>
        <datacred>Alaska Department of Community and Regional Affairs, Kenai Peninsula Borough,
Municipality of Anchorage, Bureau of Land Management.</datacred>
    </idinfo>
    <dataqual>
        <attracc>
            <attraccr>Unknown.</attraccr>
        </attracc>
        <logic>Polygon topology present.</logic>
        <complete>All boroughs are mapped.</complete>
        <posacc>
            <horizpa>
                <horizpar>unknown</horizpar>
            </horizpa>
        </posacc>
        <lineage>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>Alaska Department of Community and Regional Affairs</origin>
                        <pubdate>1995</pubdate>
                        <title>Borough and Rural Education Attendance Area Boundaries</title>
                        <serinfo>
                            <sername>Boundary</sername>
                            <issue>bororeaa</issue>
                        </serinfo>
                        <pubinfo>
                            <pubplace>Anchorage, AK</pubplace>
                            <publish>ADNR, LRIS</publish>
                        </pubinfo>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>online</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <sngdate>
                            <caldate>1995</caldate>
                        </sngdate>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>Ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>bororeaa</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Base coverage for update.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Updated new boundaries.</procdesc>
                <procdate>1997</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Modified borough boundaries, see Supplemental Information.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20050930</procdate>
                <proccont>
                    <cntinfo>
                        <cntperp>
                            <cntper>GIS Public Access Coordinator</cntper>
                            <cntorg>AK Department of Natural Resources - Information Resource Management</cntorg>
                        </cntperp>
                        <cntpos>GIS Public Access Coordinator</cntpos>
                        <cntaddr>
                            <addrtype>Mailing and physical.</addrtype>
                            <address>550 W. 7th Suite 706</address>
                            <city>Anchorage</city>
                            <state>AK</state>
                            <postal>99501</postal>
                            <country>USA</country>
                        </cntaddr>
                        <cntvoice>907 269 8833</cntvoice>
                        <cntfax>907 269 8920</cntfax>
                        <cntemail>dnr.gispub@alaska.gov</cntemail>
                        <hours>0800-1600 AST</hours>
                    </cntinfo>
                </proccont>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>The borough region subclass of BOROREAA imported into geodatabase.</procdesc>
                <procdate>unknown</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Revised by Teri Moody. Created boundary for Municipality of Skagway. Per Certificate of Incorporation of a Skagway Borough,effective June 20, 2007.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20080602</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Revised by Teri Moody. Added Petersburg Borough. Petersburg Borough incorporates approximately 3,365 square miles of land and 982 square miles of water. Approved August 22, 2012.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20130204</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Geodatabase feature classes data copied to materialized view.</procdesc>
                <procdate>unknown</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Materialized view data extracted and converted to Shape format.</procdesc>
                <procdate>unknown</procdate>
            </procstep>
        </lineage>
    </dataqual>
    <spdoinfo>
        <direct>Vector</direct>
        <ptvctinf>
            <sdtsterm>
                <sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
                <ptvctcnt>19</ptvctcnt>
            </sdtsterm>
        </ptvctinf>
    </spdoinfo>
    <spref>
        <horizsys>
            <planar>
                <mapproj>
                    <mapprojn>Albers Conical Equal Area</mapprojn>
                    <albers>
                        <stdparll>55.0</stdparll>
                        <stdparll>65.0</stdparll>
                        <longcm>-154.0</longcm>
                        <latprjo>50.0</latprjo>
                        <feast>0.0</feast>
                        <fnorth>0.0</fnorth>
                    </albers>
                </mapproj>
                <planci>
                    <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
                    <coordrep>
                        <absres>1.0E-4</absres>
                        <ordres>1.0E-4</ordres>
                    </coordrep>
                    <plandu>meters</plandu>
                </planci>
            </planar>
            <geodetic>
                <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
                <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
                <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
                <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
            </geodetic>
        </horizsys>
    </spref>
    <eainfo>
        <detailed>
            <enttyp>
                <enttypl>BOROUGH</enttypl>
                <enttypd>Feature class</enttypd>
                <enttypds>ESRI</enttypds>
            </enttyp>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>SID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>LAS Abbreviation.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>ADNR LAS database.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <edom>
                        <edomv>bororeaa.lut</edomv>
                        <edomvd>unknown</edomvd>
                        <edomvds>ADNR, LRIS</edomvds>
                    </edom>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>NAME</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Borough Name.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Alaska Department of Community and Regional Affairs and LAS.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <edom>
                        <edomv>Enumerated -- as listed</edomv>
                        <edomvd>unknown</edomvd>
                        <edomvds>ADCRA</edomvds>
                    </edom>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>TYPE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Item for selecting all Boroughs.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>ADNR LAS database.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <edom>
                        <edomv>codeset -- B = Borough</edomv>
                        <edomvd>unknown</edomvd>
                        <edomvds>ADNR LAS database</edomvds>
                    </edom>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
        </detailed>
    </eainfo>
    <distinfo>
        <distrib>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>Alaska Department of Natural Resources - Information Resource Management</cntorg>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntpos>GIS Public Access Coordinator</cntpos>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
                    <address>550 W. 7th Suite 706</address>
                    <city>Anchorage</city>
                    <state>AK</state>
                    <postal>99501</postal>
                    <country>USA</country>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>907 269 8060</cntvoice>
                <cntfax>907 269 8920</cntfax>
            </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
        <distliab>The State of Alaska makes no express or implied warranties (including warranties of merchantability
and fitness) with respect to the character, function, or capabilities of the electronic services
or products or their appropriateness for any users purposes. In no event will the State of Alaska
be liable for any incidental, indirect, special, consequential or other damages suffered by the
user or any other person or entity whether from the use of the electronic services or products,
any failure thereof or otherwise, and in no event will the State of Alaska s liability to the
requestor or anyone else exceed the fee paid for the electronic service or product.</distliab>
        <stdorder>
            <digform>
                <digtinfo>
                    <formname>zipped shape file</formname>
                </digtinfo>
                <digtopt>
                    <onlinopt>
                        <computer>
                            <networka>
<networkr>http://asgdc.alaska.gov#40</networkr>
                            </networka>
                        </computer>
                    </onlinopt>
                </digtopt>
            </digform>
            <fees>none</fees>
        </stdorder>
    </distinfo>
    <metainfo>
        <metd>20130204</metd>
        <metc>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>AK Department of Natural Resources - Information Resource Management</cntorg>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntpos>GIS Public Access Coordinator</cntpos>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
                    <address>550 W. 7th Suite 706</address>
                    <city>Anchorage</city>
                    <state>AK</state>
                    <postal>99501</postal>
                    <country>USA</country>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>907 269 8060</cntvoice>
                <cntfax>907 269 8920</cntfax>
                <cntemail>dnr.gispub@alaska.gov</cntemail>
                <hours>800-1600 AST</hours>
            </cntinfo>
        </metc>
        <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
        <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
        <mettc>local time</mettc>
        <metuc>If the user has modified the data in any way they are obligated
to describe the types of modifications they have performed in the
supporting metadata file.  User specifically agrees not to imply
that changes they made were approved by the Alaska Department of
Natural Resources.</metuc>
        <metextns>
            <onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
            <metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
        </metextns>
    </metainfo>
</MetadataType>
